SUMMARY

Young professional with work experiences across various industries including public institutions (national and international), non-for-profit organizations and the private sector. Excellent analytical and writing skills developed through consulting, policy related activities, as well as research assistance for university and business organizations. Able to integrate the work of multiple teams, to take leadership responsibilities and to provide evidence-based insights to decision-makers. Proven ability in statistical and data analysis, detailed oriented and comfortable with working in diverse contexts and in different languages.

WORK EXPERIENCE

The Brattle Group, Europe Practice Associate

Rome, Italy

July 2019 – August 2020

- Advised clients on complex economic and financial issues related to competition and economic regulatory design in infrastructure and transport sectors, including toll-roads, airports, railways and maritime activities
- Financial modelling and regulatory support for institutional clients and private companies (e.g. due diligences, state aid cases) including econometric analysis and cost of capital estimation in regulated industries
- · Estimated damages in commercial litigation and international arbitration cases for corporations, law firms and governments

Italian Government, Prime Minister office Economic Adviser

Rome, Italy

March 2016 – February 2018

- Supported the activity of the strategy unit in the process of policy design, implementation, monitoring and evaluation; contributed to frame legislation for labour market, pensions, anti-poverty, tax design and research policies included in the 2017 and 2018 Annual Budget Law (total public spending of €9bn+ per year)
- Performed data analysis and econometric micro-simulation modelling to design and implement innovative policy schemes: in the first 2 months flexible retirement scheme "APE Volontaria" simulator accessed by 100k+ individuals (30k+ certifications)
- Drafted and reviewed confidential notes, policy briefs and presentations, coordinating a team of policy experts in collaboration with other Ministries and state agencies. Prepared State missions, meetings with institutional bodies, unions and investors
- Contributed to draft the 2018 electoral program for the Democratic Party (assistant to Prof. Nannicini, member of the national secretariat); collaborated with the Digital Transformation Team on topics related to innovation and digital payments (PagoPA)

The European House – Ambrosetti, Strategy Department Consultant

Milan, Italy

February 2014 – February 2016

- Research and program-management contributions related to strategic research studies and consultancy projects presented at TEH-A flagship events "Intelligence on the World, Europe and Italy" and "The Outlook for the Economy and Finance"; drafted and reviewed 10+ reports and presentations and performed quantitative analysis on statistics and original data
- Contributed to organize and promote conferences, workshops and international Summit with Ministries, Head of States, CEOs, NGOs, academics and professionals, and interviewed opinion leaders and experts for strategic analysis

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Columbia University, School of International and Public Affairs Graduate Teaching Assistant

New York, USA

January 2019 – May 2019

• Lecturer for the graduate course *Financial Development in Emerging Economies* taught by Prof. A. De La Torre and Prof. A. Ize; led the data-lab recitations and provided research assistance on macroeconomic analysis, balance of payment crisis and financial integration trends

Confindustria, Research Department Economist

Rome, Italy

March 2018 - June 2018

• Produced notes, research papers and economic forecast for monthly release "Congiuntura Flash", policy briefs "Note CSC" and quarterly reports "Scenari Economici" on European institutional design, the Italian labour market and the spending review

• Carried out policy analysis and evaluation on productivity, fiscal and trade incentives on firm level data and managed a large enterprise survey on the labour market in Italy with over 4,000 respondents; contributed to frame and negotiate a collaboration agreement with institutional bodies such as the Ministry of Economy, the National Institute of Statistics (ISTAT), the Senate Impact Assessment Office as well as private research firms

Delegation of the European Union to China & Mongolia, Development & Cooperation Section Intern

Beijing, China July 2012 – December 2012

- Contributed to draft the first "working agreement" of the EU external action service for the award of 'IP KEY'; drafted a Cooperation arrangement between the Services of the European Union and the Chinese Ministry of Commerce
- Assisted the selection process of 20+ Key Experts and contributed to the strategy review of the 'EU SME Centre' and supported the preparation of the Annual Work Plan 3 and the Mid Term Evaluation's terms of reference for 'EUCTP II'

EDUCATION

Columbia University, School of International and Public Affairs MPA in Economic Policy Management

New York, USA

May 2019

Recipient of the SIPA-PEPM Scholarship

Bocconi University, Faculty of Economics

Milan, Italy

MSc in Economics; Thesis: "The natural resource curse and political participation: evidence from panel data"

March 2014

Exchange semester at the Stockholm School of Economics, Sweden

University of Milan, Faculty of Political Sciences

Milan, Italy

BA in European Economic Studies, Thesis: "The privatization of water services in Europe"

July 2011

Erasmus program at Universitat de Barcelona, Spain

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Languages
Italian: Native | English: Fluent (IELTS 8) | Spanish: Fluent (DELE C2)
IT
Excellent knowledge of Windows, Mac OS X, Microsoft Office and STATA

Sociable, accountable and oriented to responsibility. Goal driven, extroverted and highly adaptable to

different cultural and social environment.